Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
- Series I. Research
  - Subseries I. General
    - Supernovae, Antimatter, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Misc. astrophysics, 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Leonard Maximon, Bethe's Bremsstrahlung Spectrum, (n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Symposium material, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Dale Corson, education, 1987-1998 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Bethe Lectures, Steven M. Block, 1992-2000 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Cosmology, Brout, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - SAGE, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - 9th Edition of McGraw-Hill Encyclopedia of Science and Technology, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Galaxy, 2001, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Bethe, Lowi, Long and Kahn, (n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Graphs (not dated), (n.d.) (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Misc. nuclear matter, 1964-1975 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Heavy Nuclei, 1966-1975 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Nuclear Matter Reprints 1 of 3, 1966-1993 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Nuclear Matter Reprints 2 of 3, 1966-1993 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Nuclear Matter Reprints 3 of 3, 1966-1993 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Nuclear physics reprints, Bethe, 1967, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Burhop and Electron Scatt., Copenhagen, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Misc. nuclear matter, 1969, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Nuclear Matter, Problems 1970, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Nuclear Matter Molinari, 1970, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Nuclear Matter Talk, 1980, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Neutron Star Models, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Misc. Nuclear Matter, 1965-1974 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Stars, 1967-1976 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Science times, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Atomic Structure, 1956-1969 (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Solar Neutrinos, New Physics is Required, Bahcall - Bethe, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - Solar Neutrinos, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - Neutrino Oscillations, Weneser-Baltz, 1986-1988 (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - Maximum Neutron Star Mass, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - Low Mass Black Holes, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - Neutron Stars - Malone, Johnson and Bethe, Ap. J. 199, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Proposal to Measure the Form Factors of He-3 and -4, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - German articles (Box 116, Folder 18-19)
  - Subseries II. Notes and calculations
    - Notes on Seminars (1975-1981) 1 of 3, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Seminars (1975-1981) 2 of 3, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Seminars (1975-1981) 3 of 3, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Stony Brook, May '79, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Supernova Meeting, 17-19 Sept. '79, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Gerry Apr.-Jul. '80, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Santa Barbra Meeting, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Neutron Matter, Figures and Tables, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Notes: Radiation, Coulomb Effect, etc., (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Zuker, data printouts, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Phys Rev. Letters notes, 1958-1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Bassichis et al, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Gull Lake Symposium, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Pi-nucleus, Wilet's calc, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Dispersion Relations, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Electron-proton scattering, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Fundam. Particles, 1960-1963 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Nuclear Physics. Schumacher, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Stapp Phase Shifts etc., 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - 1987A Research, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Nuclear Matter, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Nuclear Matter, Figures, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Reading from Ann. Rev. Nuc. Sci. articles, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Nuclear Theory, given 1950, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Bethe, Lecture Notes, Brueckner, 1956-1964 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Nuclear Matter 5a (about 1966-7), 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Nuclear Matter 5b (1967), Finite Nuclei, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Nuclear Matter 6, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Misc. notes, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Nuclear Matter (1969-70), Kyoto-Rehovot-Copenhagen, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - SA - Early History and Early Calculations, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Congress for Creative America, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Electron Scattering, 1988, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Misc. notes, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Supernovae notes, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Supernovae notes, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Kepler, notes, (n.d.) (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Convection Calc., (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Figures, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Neutrino Emission, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Older SN paper, Calculations, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Wilczek, QCD, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Ms. of Festschrift for W. A. Fowler, abt. 1980, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Woosley, Reverse Shock etc, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Notes, Breakout Shock, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Mesons. Calculations, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Binaries, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Black hole notes, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Misc. Astrophysics Notes, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Misc. Notes, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Misc. Notes, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Misc. notes on nuclear physics, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - r-process, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Storage Cases (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Seminar Notes, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Kalogera, supernova explosions, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Nucleo-Synthesis, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Helium Abundance, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Additional Data Printouts I, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Additional Data Printouts II, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Additional Data Printouts III, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Data Printouts, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Wilson EOS, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Wilson--Mayle. December '88, I, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Wilson--Mayle. December '88, II, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - General Astrophysics, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Neutrino Notes, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Calc. Solar Neutrinos, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - 3-body theory, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Dahlblom, Sprung, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Data Printouts 1, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Data Printouts 2, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Data Printouts 3, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Data Printouts 4, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Data Printouts 5, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Data Printouts 6, (n.d.) (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Data Printouts 7, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Data Printouts 8, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - History of Stellar Energy, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Notes, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Feynman Lecture, History, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Evolution of single stars, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Misc. supernova, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Misc. supernova, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Quark Condensate, Hadron-Quark Transition, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Yahil, misc. notes, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - QCD, Jan. '92, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Older version of Constraint, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Historical, Effective Range Theory of Nuclear Forces 1948, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Meson Capture, energy loss of slow particles abt. 1950, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Neutron Resonances (Brookhaven), 1950-1952 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Spinless mesons, inelastic scattering, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Neutrinos, vugraphs Seattle, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Supernovae vugraphs, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Nucleosynthesis, Benz vugraphs, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Mergers ms, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Ms. extra copies, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Convection, supernovae, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - r-process etc., (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Road from Los Alamos, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Slides for Columbus, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Solar neutrinos, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Solar Neutrino Ohio, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Bethe and Wilets, limits on compression, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Neutrinos, Geneseo colloquium, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Travel, Neutrino '88, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Solar Neutrinos, 1990, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Notes and Calculations, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Notes and Calculations, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Notes and Calculations, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Stony Brook 1993, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Calc. on Contraints, Wilson notes, 1993, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Constraints, SN shock, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Constraints on SN, handwritten, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - 1995 calculations, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Misc. astrophysics, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Data Printouts, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Misc. Notes, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - H. Hoerlin, high altitude phenomenology, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Livermore x-ray Laser, 16-2-83, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - MIT notes, 1997, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Extras for Mergers, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Mergers Vugraphs, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Nuclear Matter, U. Mass. Nov '75, Japan Oct '77, 1975, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Subseries III. Articles by Bethe
    Articles Bethe wrote for publication. Occasionally includes notes and correspondence directly related to the articles.
    - Misc Bethe articles, 1957-1967 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Book Reviews, Short Papers, (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Yearian, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Nuclear testing (Bethe article), (n.d.) (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - High Energy Phenomena, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Mesons and Protons, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Misc. Bethe Reprints, 1956-1959 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Doppler Effect, Fast Reactors, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - Detection of Atomic Weapons Tests, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - Bethe articles, 1935-1940 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - Deviations from thermal equilibrium in shock waves--H.A. Bethe and E. Teller, 1940-1947 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - The Theory of Shock waves for Arbitrary Equation of State--H.A. Bethe, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bethe reports, blast waves and fireballs, 1947-1967 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Weisskopf, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Pion Scattering, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Neutrino fluxes, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Ms. r-process, unpublished, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Bethe et al articles on supernovae, 1982-1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - SN II, Preservation of SN shock, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Supernova Theory, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Quantum Theory, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - References, changes, 1995, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Supernova Shock VIII, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - #3, Nuclear Physics, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Evolution of Binary Compact Objects...Bethe and Brown draft, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Contribution of High-Mass Black Holes to Mergers of compact binaries (drafts), Bethe/Brown, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Articles about me, Publications list, Bethe, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - History of Stellar Energy, 1937, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - History of Energy in Stars, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - 100yr. Phys. Rev., 1995 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Convection for Astrophysical Journal, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Ms. Late Shock, Unpublished, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Supernova paper II, Features of the SN shock, not published, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Astrophysical Journal paper A, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Bethe, supernovae, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Electromagnetic Shift of Energy Levels, Bethe, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Ann. Reviews, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Bethe. Figures for Ann. Rev., 1988 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Convection: draft and notes, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Breakout copies, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Location of the r-process, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Preservation of SN shock Ap. J. II, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - SN Shock VI, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - The Supernova Shock, Ms., (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - SN Figures, mostly 1981, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Neutrinos paper (future 2), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Physics Today, Amsterdam, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Physics Today, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Breakout, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Bethe, Compton Lecturer, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Bethe, Sommerfeld and Pauli, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Bethe Papers (1957-1971) 1 of 2, 1957-1971 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Bethe Papers (1957-1971) 2 of 2, 1957-1971 (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Nuclear Matter Calculations, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Bethe Review, Mathematical Physics, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - Bethe, 'Quantum Mechanics of one-and two-electron systems', (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Relativity, (n.d.) (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - Supernovae, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - Penetrations of Fast Particles Through Matter, 1930 (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - Bethe's U. of Manchester Notebook, 1933-1934 (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - Nuclear Matter, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - Computers and Science, Bethe Intro, (n.d.) (Box 53, Folder 37)
    - Bethe Review of A-bomb Book, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 38)
    - Review: Weisskopf, Privilege of Being a Physicist, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 39)
    - 100 Years of Phys. Rev., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 40)
    - Quantum Theory, zero temperature, 1931 (Box 53, Folder 41)
    - Siemens Article, Italian Encyclopedia, 1971, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 42)
    - 1986 paper, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 43)
    - Solar Neutrino, HAB PRL 63, 837, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 44)
    - Solar Neutrinos, International Journal of Modern Physics D, Vol. 1, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 45)
    - Presentation of SN Shock 1993, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 46)
    - Bethe article clippings, 1948-1954 (Box 113, Folder 44)
    - Bethe article clippings, with photograph from 1962, 1958-1961 (Box 113, Folder 45)
    - Bethe article clippings, 1940s-1950s (Box 114, Folder 4-5)
    - Bethe articles, 1960s (Box 114, Folder 1-3, 6)
    - Bethe article clippings, 1970s (Box 114, Folder 7-10)
    - Bethe article clippings, 1980s (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - Bethe papers and publication lists, 2000s (Box 114, Folder 12-15)
    - Physics Reports: Bethe's centennial volume, 2006 (Box 114, Folder 16)
    - Bethe clippings on Nuclear Weapons, 1946-1955 (Box 114, Folder 17)
    - Bethe on Atomic Bomb politics, including testimony, 1945-1946 (Box 114, Folder 18)
    - Bethe at Cornell articles and two photographs, 1960s (Box 114, Folder 19)
  - Subseries IV. Articles by others
    Includes articles and publications Bethe gathered, related to his research interests and conferences he attended.
    - Misc. physic reprints 1 of 4, 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Misc. physic reprints 2 of 4, 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Misc. physic reprints 3 of 4, 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Misc. physic reprints 4 of 4, 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Papers and Reports, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Science, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Heavy Atom Collisions, (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Van Riper, (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wilson and Bowers, (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - History of Science (1938-1981) 1 of 2, 1938-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - History of Science (1938-1981) 2 of 2, 1938-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Astrophysics Reprints, 1965-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Supporting Papers, astrophysics, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Negative Shock Waves, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Astrophysics, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - History, Solid State Physics, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Supernova, Applegate, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Reprints, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Reprints, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Reprints and Bibliography, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Misc Article Reprints, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Misc Article Reprints, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Misc Publications and articles, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Meteoritic Crystals, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Misc Research, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Papers on Bethe by Karl Hafbauer - "Hans Bethe's Breakthrough on the Stellar-Energy Problem", Bethe Chronology/Biography, and Bethe reception chronology, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Princeton File 1: Assembled Articles, 1953-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Princeton File 1: Misc Publications, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Princeton File 1: Nuclear Energy and the Future Series, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Princeton File 1: Office of Naval Research, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Princeton File 1: Reports and papers, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Princeton File 1: Misc articles, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Princeton File 2: DCTR Fussion-Fission, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Princeton File 2: Komzin articles, USSR, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Princeton File 2: Sands, Synchrotron, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Princeton File 2: Project Cowboy, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Princeton File 2: Avco, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Princeton File 2: Bureau of Mines, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Princeton File 2: Misc publications, 1957-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Princeton File 3: Part 1, 1934-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Princeton File 3: Part 2, 1931-1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Princeton File 3: Part 3, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Nucl. Matter Info, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - History of Nuclear Physics, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Preprints, Neutron Stars, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Pandha, Siemens, nuclear matter, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Canadian Journal of Physics, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Johnson, neutron star paper, Pandha, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Walecka, electron scattering, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - NSF proposals, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Neutron Stars, Illinois Info., 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Misc. Research, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Ultradense matter, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Richard Beals, electron scattering, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Weiner papers, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Neutron Stars, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Johnson, Star Paper, Los Alamos, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Nucl. Matter, finite nuclei, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Radiation Handbooks, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Quantum Mechanics (Rosenfeld), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - High Energy Information, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The case against antimatter in the universe, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Potentials, Reid, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 58 [articles], 1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 59 [articles], 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 64 [articles], 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Tradex Manual, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Misc. nuclear matter, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Nuclear Matter, Work of Others, 1956-1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Japan Conf., (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Cooperstein, misc. astrophysics, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Van Riper-Lattimer, Infall, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cooperstein between III and IV, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Data Printouts, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Ruoff, 1992, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Papers (by others) on Politics, Universities, Atomic Energy, etc., 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Koonin et al, Shell Model Monte Carlo, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Neutron Stars (Malone), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Dimotakis, turbulence, 1976-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Basic Info on Astrophysics and SN, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Neutron Star magnetic fields, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Langer, stars, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Nomoto and U. of Tokyo, SN Type I, 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Convection in SN, Correspondence '87, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - SN Burrows, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Ainsworth BBCP, Relatives, Lattimer, Prakash, Neutron Stars, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - SN 1987A, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Astrophysics, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Misc. astrophysics, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Suzuki thesis, Neutron Burst, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Nomoto, SN 1987A, 1989, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Basic Info on Astrophysics, 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Binary Planetary Nebulae, Iben, Tutukov, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Double Neutron Stars, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Burrows, core collapse, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - K- Condesation, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Nucleo-Synthesis, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Woosley thesis 1973, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Propagation of Star Formation, Seiden, 1983, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Thielemann, Thermonuclear Reaction Rates, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Nomoto, Supernovae, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Level matrix, beta decay, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Woolsey, Galactic Chemistry, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Stellar Collapse, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Herant, Supernovae, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - SN 1987A, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Herant and Woosley, Rayleigh-Tayler instabilities, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Woosley-Weaver, nucleo-synth '95, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Kinoshita '96, Fine Structure Constant, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Nucleo-Synthesis, Basic Info., 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Chernoff, neutron star population dynamics, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Misc research articles, 1986-1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Nuclear Physics articles, 1994, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Gravitational Waves, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Misc Quantum Physics, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Wasserburg, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Articles: neutrinos, black holes, etc., 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Misc Superconductors, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Misc., 1983-1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Misc articles for research, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Misc astrophysics, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Gottfried, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Corson, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Epstein: Early Climate, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Quantum, 1982-1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Negele, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Electron Scattering (Jacob) Stopping, 1959-1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - 3-Body, Kirson, Dahlblom, Rajarman, 1963, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Electron Scattering, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 3-body problem, 1970, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Pions, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Pandha, nuclear matter, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Negele, electron scattering, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Delbruck Scattering, 1975-1990 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Deuteron magnetic form factor, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Pieper-Pandha proposal, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Dark Matter, Neutron Star number, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Lattimer, Burrows and Yahil, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Quark Masses, Gasser-Leutwyler et al, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Colgate SN papers, 1960, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Misc. astrophysics, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Helium Monolayers, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Bodmer, nuclear collapse, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Pandha Method, Verlet, Schiff, Kalos, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Black Holes, Gerry, 1977-1993 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Important SN papers, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Astrophysics Papers 1981, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Astrophysics, other papers, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Supernova, Supporting Papers, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Lamb Shift, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Gerry, Nolen-Schiffer effect, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)